A Guide to the Charles H. Moody Papers, 1862-1889
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Charles H. Moody Papers, 1862-1889
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Moody, Charles H. (8th NY Cavalry)
Ms2017-003
0.3 Cubic Feet 1 box
The Charles H. Moody Papers contain correspondence from Charles H. Moody to his father, mother, brother, and various friends relating to his service in Fredericksburg, Gettysburg, and throughout Virginia, datingranges from January 1862-June 1865.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Charles H. Moody Papers were purchased by Special Collections in 2016.
Scope and Content
The Charles H. Moody Papers contain correspondence from Charles H. Moody to his father, mother, brother, and various friends relating to his service in Fredericksburg, Gettysburg, and throughout Virginia, dating from January 1862-June 1865. The Charles H. Moody Papers also include military papers with information about the 8th N.Y. Volunteer Cavalry and drawings.
Arrangement Note
The Charles H. Moody Papers are arranged by type of material. Within the correspondence folders, materials are arranged in chronological order.
Biographical Note
Charles H. Moody was born on September 9, 1843. He was a bugler and orderly in the 8th N.Y. Volunteer Cavalry during the American Civil War. He enlisted at the age of 18 on August 23, 1862 and was mustered out in June 27, 1865 in Alexandria, VA. On June 1, 1864, he was captured and sent to a Confederate POW Camp in Florence, South Carolina. By the end of the war, he had earned the rank 2nd Lieutenant. Following the war he married Helen M. Hall and they had one daughter. He worked as a bookkeeper for a lumber company. He passed away on June 1, 1908.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Civil War; Gettysburg, Battle of, Gettysburg, Pa., 1863; Gettysburg Campaign, 1863; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental Histories
Genre and Form Terms:
Correspondence
- Correspondence, 1862-1865
  - 1862-01-06-1862-11-25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1862-12-02-1862-12-30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1863-01-07-1863-06-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1863-07-04-1863-10-22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1863-11-01-1863-12-14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1864-01-15-1864-03-18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1864-04-02-1864-11-08 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1865-01-19-1865-06-14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Undated, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Military Papers, 1863-1889 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ephemera, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)